svNull ""
svNewGame "New Game"
svSingleGame "Single Player"
svNetGame "Multiplayer"
svNetCreate "Create"
svConnect "Join"
svHintRefreshing "Searching for hosts..."
svHintHostListEmpty "No hosts found"
svContinue "Continue"
svLoad "Load"
svOptions "Settings"
svControls "Controls"
svMaxPlayers "Maximum number of players"
svApply "Accept"
svAuthors "Authors"
svExit "Exit"
svProfile "Profile: %s"
svGraphic "Graphics"
svResolution "Resolution"
svShadow "Shadows"
svEnv "Environment"
svLight "Lighting"
svPostProcess "Post-Processing"
svGPUSync "GPU Sync"
svSound "Sound"
svGame "Game"
svNetwork "Sound"
svMusic "Music"
svSoundFX "Effects"
svFixedFrameRate "Fixed framerate"
svSoundDicter "Commentator volume level"
svFiltering "Anisotropic filtering"
svMultisampling "Multisampling"
svUpgradeMaxLevel "Maximum upgrade level"
svWeaponMaxLevel "Maximum number of weapon slots"
svMaxPLayers "Number of human players"
svMaxComputers "Number of AI players"
svCommentator "Commentator"
svSpringBorders "Hard borders"
svLanguage "Language"
svCamera "Camera"
svChampionship "Tournament"
svSkirmish "Single race"
svWorkshop "Workshop"
svGarage "Garage"
svCasePlanet "Change planet"
svRewards "Achievements"
svInfoPlayer "Player"
svInfoPlayerText "Planet: %s\nStage: %d - Race: %d/%d\n%s%s\n%s%s"
svInfoRace "Race"
svInfoRaceText "Place:           I              II            III\nMoney:  $%d   $%d   $%d\nPoints:         %d          %d         %d\nWeather:  %s"
svCarCost "Cost:\n%d$"
svOk "OK"
svCancel "Cancel"
svBack "Back"
svYes "Yes"
svNo "No"
svBuy "Buy"
svPlayer "Player"
svPassing "Planet"
svTournament "Tournament"
svWeapons "Weapons"
svBossName "Boss"
svBuyWeapon "Buy this weapon for\n%s?"
svBuyCar "Buy this car for\n%s?"
svSellWeapon "Sell this weapon for\n%s?"
svLow "Low"
svMiddle "Medium"
svHigh "High"
svOn "On"
svOff "Off"
svRussian "Russian"
svEnglish "English"
svCameraSecView "Rear view"
svCameraOrtho "Isometric view"
svWarning "Warning"
svHintYouNotCompletePass "The season is over. You don't have enough points to advance to the next division."
svHintYouCompletePass "The season is over. Division B is completed!"
svHintYouCanFlyPlanet "The season is over. Division A is completed! Now you can advance to the next planet."
svYouReadyFlyPlanet "Are you ready to go to this planet?"
svYouReadyStayPlanet "Are you sure you want to stay on this planet?"	
svReadyRace "Player is ready for race"
svCancelReadyRace "Player is not ready for race"
svHostLabel "Host"
svHintDisconnect "Disconnected from host"
svHintPlayersIsNotReady "Other players are not ready to start the race"
svHintHostListEmpty "host list is empty"
svHintHostConnectionFailed "Unable to connect: all slots are taken or you have a bad connection"
svHintSetColorFailed "This color is used by another player"
svHintSetGamerFailed "This character is used by another player"
svHintPleaseWait "please wait"
svHintWeaponNotSupport "The weapon is not supported by this car"
scWheaterFair "Fair"
scWheaterNight "Night"
scWheaterClody "Cloudy"
scWheaterRainy "Rainy"
scWheaterMapEdit "None"
scEarth "Earth"
scPatagonis "Patagonis"
scIntaria "Intaria"
scHemi5 "Chemi 5"
scInferno "Inferno"
scNho "NHO"
scPatagonisInfo "A gloomy postnuclear world that was flooded intensely centuries ago. The scarce patches of solid ground can still be found in the vast ocean, but these islets of scorched earth have for ages been not suitable for living. Ruined buildings of an extinct civilization is all that is left on Patagonis."
scIntariaInfo "Intaria is one of the few planets that retained their pristine beauty. Covered with trackless jungles, the planet is still tenuously populated, and the few intelligent inhabitants of Intaria live in harmony with the nature and with the exotic creatures sharing these lands with them."
scHemi5Info "There probably is no other planet in universe where one can enjoy such picturesque scenery and beautiful sunsets. On Chemi 5 ancient arts intertwine with technologies of the space age in a most peculiar way."
scInfernoInfo "An infernal furnace, and at the same time planet with valuable natural resources which attract an ever-growing number of fortune seekers. Inferno’s burning hot surface did not prevent construction of the most difficult race tracks in the galaxy. "
scMarauder "Marauder"
scNhoInfo "A planet located far from its sun and almost entirely covered by snow. The permafrost world of NHO provides ideal conditions for creating race tracks using the local building materials - several thousand years old blocks of ice."
svLockedCarName "Locked"
scBuggi "Buggy"
scDirtdevil "Dirt Devil"
scTankchetti "Tankcetti"
scManticora "Manticora"
scManticoraBoss "Murdoch's Manticora"
scGuseniza "Track Tank"
scGusenizaBoss "Stinkle's Track Tank"
scPodushka "Hovercraft"
scPodushkaBoss "K-Jin's Hovercraft"
scMonsterTruck "Monstertruck"
scMonsterTruckBoss "Butcher's Monstertruck"
scDevilDriver "Devil Driver"
scDevilDriverBoss "Sidewinder"
scAirblade "Airblade"
scMustang "Mustang"
svLockedCarInfo "This car is not available"
scMarauderInfo "A true legend in the world of survival racing. Some racers love Marauder so much so they even don’t use any other cars during the tournament! For this price it is impossible to find a faster and more maneuverable vehicle."
scDirtdevilInfo "An inexpensive and popular car that was remoulded for survival racing, getting a new name and a new life. Its unsightly appearance and antique engine are compensated for by a good basic weapon and an extra slot for beam gun or rocket launcher."
scManticoraInfo "This modern car was designed specifically for survival racing. It became a fit alternative to the renowned Air Blade. The firepower of its default blaster can be complemented with two more types of weapon. The controllability of Manticora is one of the highest among the wheeled cars."
scAirbladeInfo "An updated model of the ageless classic of survival racing. The car's new body can be equipped with two additional types of light weapons. Air Blade's default weapon is a rather slow missile launcher that is, however, just sufficient to leave smoking piles of car remnants in its wake."
scGusenizaInfo "The modernized version of heavy tank proved to be greatly helpful in warfare as well as in survival racing. Its heavy armor and excellent road grip put it on par with the most powerful of vehicles available. It supports most weapon types and is accordingly expensive."
scPodushkaInfo "A swift and light air-propelled unit equipped with advanced self-guided ammunition. The streamlined body helps its cornering ability, but its low weight does not allow heavy weapons to be installed on this vehicle. The car’s armor is one of the flimsiest in its price tier."
scMonsterTruckInfo "A monster assembled of various parts of cars and military equipment. One of the most armored vehicles ever used in survival racing. Despite its heaviness it has a good controllability; the power of its basic armaments is destructive. Because of its high price many of the racers prefer cheaper and at the same time more technologically advanced vehicles."
scDevilDriverInfo "Devildriver is a custom-made car put together by a mad engineer. It combines the latest space technologies with retro design concepts. It is equipped with remodelled version of the singular engine used in starships; it allows the car to float above the ground. Its energy weapon has devastating power."
scSidewinderInfo "Sidewinder is creature of the best mechanics. Latest advances in science helped this car affect to gravity. Flying car is equipped with the highest level of armor and also has the best weapons around the galaxy."
scMustangInfo "This troglodytic hot rod was living his last days rusting at city dump, however it took Chuck Wuzz and his crew only a week to turn it into a masterpiece of automobile design!"
scBuggiInfo "A small-lot production car which originally was designed for safari. However, it didn't get much popularity in survival racing. Some say the problem is the car's open body."
scTankchettiInfo "A piece of scrap metal that survived from the times beyond memory and was remade into a battle car. Its design resembles a mainstream hatchback from the early XXI century on Earth."
scEngine1 "Engine 1"
scEngine2 "Engine 2"
scEngine3 "Engine 3"
scWheel1 "Wheels 1"
scWheel2 "Wheels 2"
scWheel3 "Wheels 3"
scArmor1 "Armor 1"
scArmor2 "Armor 2"
scArmor3 "Armor 3"
scArmor4 "Titanide"
scTruba1 "Exhaust Pipe 1"
scTruba2 "Exhaust Pipe 2"
scTruba3 "Exhaust Pipe 3"
scGuseniza1 "Treads 1"
scGuseniza2 "Treads 2"
scGuseniza3 "Treads 3"
scGuseniza4 "Treads 4"
scEngine1Info "The default engine just sufficient for racing"
scEngine2Info "A custom-made eight-cylinder engine"
scEngine3Info "This V-twin eight-cylinder engine with an increased capacity ensures the best dynamic characteristics of a car"
scWheel1Info "Wheels from the basic car configuration along with mass production tires intended for regular roads"
scWheel2Info "Disks made from a special alloy and complemented with high quality tires, making for a better road grip"
scWheel3Info "Lightweight disks and exclusive tires with titanium spikes are the best option available for survival racing"
scArmor1Info "A built-in protection frame that ensures safety for most of the car’s components"
scArmor2Info "Armor with additional layers of protection against various ammunition types"
scArmor3Info "Unique armor that is made from a rare material and includes many protection elements"
scArmor4Info "The most exquisite armor for which many would be willing to trade their souls"
scTruba1Info "System included in the basic configuration, it provides acceptable exhaust gas recirculation"
scTruba2Info "An exhaust system fitted with an additional exhaust box to speed up fume extraction from exhaust manifold"
scTruba3Info "The best exhaust pipe made from high quality ligtweight alloy. Provides additional diffusion and deflation of exhausted fuel"
scGuseniza1Info "Fairly good standard tracks installed on most military vehicles. Designed for severe operating conditions"
scGuseniza2Info "Tracks enhanced with special electromagnetic treatment. Notable for their light weight"
scGuseniza3Info "Spiked tracks made from a special alloy. Designed for achieving high acceleration"
scGuseniza4Info "Keklurk Test"
scBulletGun "Machine gun"
scRifle "Rifle"
scBlaster "Beam gun"
scAirWeapon "Missile launcher"
scTankLaser "Laser"
scSonar "Sonar"
scRocket "Rocket launcher"
scPulsator "Pulsator"
scFireGun "Flamethrower"
scDrobilka "Grinder"
scSphereGun "Ion Gun"
scReflector "Reflector"
scRezonator "Phaser"
scDroid "Droid"
scPhazer "Phaser"
scTorpeda "Torpedo"
scMaslo "Oil"
scAcidOil "Acidic Oil"
scMineSpike "Spike"
scMineRip "Spider mine"
scHyper "Hyperdrive"
scHyper2 "Hyper nitro"
scTurel "Turret"
scMortira "Mortar gun"
scPhaseImpulse "Phase radiator"
scHyperBlaster "Supersonic blaster"
scMinePropton "Protonic mine"
scSpring "Spring mechanism"
scBulletGunInfo "A light machinegun that is fixed on the hood of the car. Weak firepower is compensated for by a great reserve of ammunition"
scRifleInfo "Despite their modest firepower the explosive bullets of this rifle can send adversary into a ditch for a long time"
scBlasterInfo "A twinned energetic weapon with good precision and firepower"
scTankLaserInfo "Generates a continuous beam of significant length that inflicts accumulative damage"
scAirWeaponInfo "A fairly old but still useful weapon with decent firepower"
scSonarInfo "A threatening energy weapon that has a special characteristic: its projectiles rebound from constructive elements of race tracks"
scRocketInfo "The rocket projectiles of this gun have a fairly good speed and destructive potential for its relatively low price"
scPulsatorInfo "A good starting weapon with which precision fire is particularly easy owing to the long energetic beams it generates"
scFireGunInfo "Releases waves of fire covering a short distance, which damage everything in their path"
scDrobilkaInfo "A contact weapon that deals massive amounts of damage to vehicles for 3 seconds"
scSphereGunInfo "Shoots self-guided bunches of energy moving at a rather low speed"
scTorpedaInfo "Homing rocket that deals huge amount of damage but has a low speed"
scMasloInfo "Be careful! Spilled oil can cause loss of control of the car"
scAcidOilInfo "Driving on a puddle of acidic oil causes a loss of car's hit points"
scMineSpikeInfo "Inflicts damage to cars coming across it"
scMineRipInfo "Fragments are released three seconds after it is placed on the ground. The fragments detonate on impact"
scHyperInfo "Gives extra acceleration to the car"
scHyper2Info "A new stronger level of extra acceleration for the car"
scTurelInfo "Shoots deadly bullets that have very high movement speed"
scMortiraInfo "Launches a cannon ball that follows a parabolic trajectory and inflicts mass damage, also leaving a fiery trail that damages cars"
scPhaseImpulseInfo "Shoots bundles of energy which deal damage to several opponents"
scHyperBlasterInfo "A devastating energy weapon that launches bundles of radioactive energy"
scMineProptonInfo "This mine is fitted with motion sensor. On impact it deals significant damage to the nearest objects"
scSpringInfo "Pneumatic springs can lift your car in the air for a short time"
scReflectorInfo "A unique robotized device used for blast wave suppression. Decreases damage taken from any mines by 60%"
scDroidInfo "A repair droid from space battle-jets, which restores 2 armor units every second" 
scRezonatorInfo "Projectiles of this rare weapon can pass through any artificial barriers, including ramps"   
scSnake "Snake"
scTarquin "Tarquin"
scRip "Rip"
svTyler "Tyler"
svKristoph "Cristoph"
scViolet "Violet"
scGarry "Gerry Shooter"
scViper "Viper"
scMardock "Murdoch"
scStinkle "Stinkle"
scKjin "K-Jin"
scGank "Gank"
scButcher "Butcher"
scShred "Shred"
svOpen "Open"
svClosed "Closed"
svUnavailable "Unavailable. Champion's title is required"
svUnavailableTitulA "Division A"
svCompleted "Completed"
svRequestPoints "%d pts"
svPrice "Reward"
svMoney "Money"
svPoints "Points"
svYourMoneys "Your account"
svLap "Number of laps"
svHintCantStart "You cannot start race without a car with baseline upgrades: wheels, exhaust pipe, engine, armor"
svHintCantContinue "Cannot resume game. No saved profiles are available"
svHintCantNewGame "Cannot start a new game. All profile slots are already in use"
svHintCantFlyPlanet "This planet is not available yet"
svHintCantMoney "Not enough money"
svHintNeedReload "The changes will take effect after the game is restarted"
svHintExitRace "Are you sure you want to quit the race?"
svSteamErrorMessage "No steam connection found. The game will be terminated"	
svHintUpgrade "Upgrade the item"
svCredits "CREDITS\n\nProgramming\nLexer\n\nGame Design\nR.I.P.real\n\nLaboratory 24\nTok@pb\nVit.Aver\nOspaser\n\nArt\nR.I.P.real\nLivekeep\nAmbient_art\nAlienImpact\nGeckorus\n\nSite and Community\nBimmy\n\nX-Ray Dev Studios\nXGForce\nbamalf\n\nMusic\nFrantick\nSpeed Stroke\n\nVoiceover\nNotnap\nJason Heine\n\nTranslation\nNirahlos(eng)\na.postmodernist  (eng)\nNasim Kaliev (eng)\nLuís Felipe dos Santos (pt-br)\nLeonardo Kerber (pt-br)\nnikubik (fr)\nSpunky (de)\nPablo Navarro (es)\n\nThanks to\nEnemy(GorDen)\nBertoneSX\nZNGRU\nInSulD\nHisham Al-Kubeyyer\nflint\nTranceformer\nTulpar\nMagnum\nREENKmc\nDaniellf\nNekit\n\n\nSoundtrack\nFrantick - Bad to The Bone\nFrantick - Peter Gunn Theme\nSpeed Stroke - Age of Rock'n'Roll\nFrantick - Radar Love v1\nFrantick - Radar love v2\nFrantick - Paranoid\nSpeed Stroke - Riot In Everyone\nFrantick - Highway Star\nFrantick - Born to Be Wild\nFrantick- Ace of spider\nS.S.H. - Paranoid\nThe Ventures - Peter Gunn Theme\nKristopher Dahl - Are you Ready?(GMC)\nLucio Antokini - Burn (GMC)\nHardbone - This is Rock n Roll\nSong For You - Vse dorogi\n\nRRR Forever!\n\nYard Team 2013\n www.yardteam.ru"
svPassInfo "Planet: %s\nRace: %d/%d\nWeather:"
svTournamentInfo "Division: %s\nNeed: %d points\nHave: %d points"
scSnakeInfo "Even the most uninformed outcasts from the farthermost galaxies heard about Snake - and rightly so, as he was holding the top spots in tournaments for a long time. It’s probably impossible to find another human who is as obsessed with racing as Snake."
scTarquinInfo "A former star of interplanetary races who decided to revert to his old ways and refresh his memory of the old days when his victories were at the focus of attention in the whole galaxy. Undoubtedly, Tarquinn can still teach his younger opponents a trick or two."
svTylerInfo "A former space ranger who once fought against an alien race of invaders and who is currently stagnating on a remote planet of the Solar system. Participation in the races is his chance to rejoin the glorious ranks. Tyler likes cars and hates hostile aliens, and for him this is a good enough motivation to win."
"svKristophInfo "A dodger and slick opportunist who would never miss an occasion to do dirt on his opponents. Christoph’s craftiness knows no bounds, and in survival racing it is the most valuable skill."
scVioletInfo "Seeing a woman among the racers is as uncommon as winning a race without firing a single shot. However, Violet is of the kind that can give a very hard time even to most experienced racers."
scGarryInfo "No one knows what brought him into the racing and, more importantly, where he is from. Gerry himself says that he comes from far-off wildlands which would make Hell look like a most peaceful place in universe."
scViperInfo "Viper is always in the shadows"
svDiscreteVideoDetection "Integrated graphics found. If the application was normally started on this video card and the system has a discrete video card it is recommended to switch to it, or you should disable the fixed framerate mode (it makes animations smoother, responsive control of up to)"
svActivate "Disable"
svIgnore "Ignore"
svNamePlaceMarker "%d place\n%s"
svPlace1 "1st"
svPlace2 "2nd"
svPlace3 "3rd"
svPlace4 "4th"
svPlace5 "5th"
svPlace6 "6th"
svPlace7 "7th"
svPlace8 "8th"
gaAccel "Acceleration"
gaBreak "Break"
gaWheelLeft "Turn left"
gaWheelRight "Turn Right"
gaShot "Shot"
gaShot1 "Shot from first weapon"
gaShot2 "Shot from second weapon"
gaShot3 "Shot from third weapon"
gaShot4 "Shot from fourth weapon"
gaShotAll "Shot from all weapons"
gaHyper "Hyperdrive/Jump"
gaMine "Mine/Oil"
gaWeaponDown "Previous weapon"
gaWeaponUp "Next weapon"
gaViewSwitch "Change camera mode"
gaEscape "Exit from race"
gaResetCar "Reset car position"
gdEasy "Veteran"
gdNormal "Expert"
gdHard "Master"
svTylerBonus "+1 damage\n+1 armor"
scSnakeBonus "+1 speed\n+1 armor"
scTarquinBonus "+1 speed\n+1 damage"
scGarryBonus "+2 armor"
svKristophBonus "+ 2 damage"
scVioletBonus "+2 speed"
scViperBonus "+1 damage\n+1 armor\n+1 speed"
svPressKey "Press key"
svDeleteKey "Delete"
gaAction "Action"
svDifficulty "Difficulty"
svConnectIP "Connect by IP"
svEnterIP "Enter ip address,\nfor example 192.168.0.1"
svBuyReward "Are you sure you want to buy this reward?"
sfrNone "Disable"
sfrFixed "For discrete"
sfrFixedAndGPUWait "For integrated"
svSyncFrameWarning "You changed the option 'Fixed FPS' from the default 'For discrete' setting. Wrong value may result in lagging"
svHintConnecting "Connecting..."
svHintDeleteProfile "Are you sure you want to delete this profile?"
svSelectItem "Select"
svStartOptionsInfo "To continue you need to select camera mode. Isometric view (classical) is for tactical race mode, rear view (third-person view) is more arcade."
svLapsCount "Laps count"
scAsyncFrostInfo "A powerful freezing beam that slows the target"
svEnableHUD "Enable HUD"
svEnableMineBug "Enable mine bug"
svStartOptionsInfo "In order to continue the game select your preferred camera mode"
svLapsCount "Lap"
svSteamSavingMessage "Steam data is not sent. Do you really want to quit?"
svSteamErrorMessage "Unable to connect to Steam. The game is over"
svLocalServer "LAN server"
svSteamServer "Steam server"
svConnectLan "Connect LAN "
svConnectSteam "Connect Steam"
svConnectSteamLan "Connect LAN"
svSteamConnectFailed "Connect failed"
svStartMatch "Start race"
svSteamLobby "Create Lobby"
svConnectLobby "Connect to Lobby"
svHintCantPoints "Not enough points"
svWindowMode "Windowed mode"
svDisableVideo "Disable video"
svCameraDist "Camera distance"
scPlanetX "Planet X"
scPlanetXInfo " "
scXCar "X Car"
scXCarInfo " "